Guide to the Eyes of Texas television show episodes and summaries collection, 1978-2009 MS 170
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- 1980 episodes, 227099
  - Sept. 13, 1980: Arrowhead Maker, Gustine / Elam - PBGC-Oil School, Midland / Jim Reeves-Country Singer, Galloway / Terry Taylor-Insects, Fort Davis / Longhorn Cavern, Hill Country, 227113 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 081)
  - Oct. 04, 1980: Collett-Grafitti Project, Sheffield / Ranger V-Deep Sea Fishing, Galveston / G Zesch-Woodcarver, Mason / Wild Bill Longley, Giddings / Buchanan, Baker - Windmills, Spearman, 227112 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 084)
  - Oct. 11, 1980: W Casey, Pearl Diver, Kingsland / Union Hill, Burton / Spoetzl-Shiner Brewery / Tumbleweed Smith, Big Spring / Museum of the Big Bend, Alpine, 227111 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 085)
  - Oct. 18, 1980: Haynes, Big Bend Telco, Alpine / Paco-Bi-Lingual Parrot, Commerce / History of Hye / Doonan-Artist/Jag Restoreer, Austin / Bob Wills, Turkey, 227110 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 086)
  - Oct. 25, 1980: Galvez Hotel, Galveston / B Price-Indian Historian, Atlanta TX / Armontrout-Cactus Garden, Geroge West / TL Baker-Sod Farmer, Canyon / Fort Croghan, Burnet, 227109 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 087)
  - Nov. 01, 1980: Cleaver-Edsel Collector, Craft / Richmond Historical Sites / Mrs. Tucker Shortening, Sherman / Friday Mountain Camp, Driftwood / Fort richardson, Jacksboro, 227108 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 088)
  - Nov. 08, 1980: Texas Ranger Museum, Waco / Gambill Goose Refuge, Paris / Dale Eldred-Sun Artist, Corpus / M & F Clark, Primitive Art, Jefferson / Long Barrack Museum, San Antonio, 227107 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 089)
  - Nov. 15, 1980: Collett - Pictographs-Meyer Springs, Dryden / Fayetteville / Dik Hanna-Model Ships, Tyler / Miller's Zoo, Bonham, 227106 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 090)
  - Nov. 22, 1980: Eilenberger, Broyles - Eilenberger's Bakery, Palestine / Ben Franklin Post Office / Packsaddle Hang Gliders, Kingland / Epps/Cantrell-Glass Blowers, Freeport / Limpia Hotel, Fort Davis, 227105 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 091)
  - Nov. 29, 1980: Come & Take It Canon, Gonzales / Fairchilds, East Texas / B Hydrick-RX & Artist, Portland / White-Apples, Fredericksburg / Chalk Bluff Park, Uvalde, 227104 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 092)
  - Dec. 06, 1980: Bob Gidney-Jukeboxes, West / Blanco Courthouse / Mollard-Ceiling Fans, Palestine / Boquillas Canyon - Big Bend Park, 227103 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 093)
  - Dec. 13, 1980: Texas Department of Highways / Jolly Ranch, Lubbock / Fort Brown, Brownsville / Day-Machine Gun Range, Garland / Merriman-House/Mill, San Marcos, 227102 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 094)
  - Dec. 20, 1980: Fobbs-Togetherness Inc., Crockett / Waxahachie Courthouse / Granite School, Marble Falls / Shinsky/Lansing-Planes, Houston / Fossatti-Oldest TX Deli, Victoria, 227101 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 095)
  - Dec. 27, 1980: Velvin - Pea Patch Restaurant, Athens / Nameless, Texas / Hemphill Jail, Sabine Co. / Charlie Lewis-DJ, Victoria / Limdbergh Lands-Camp Wood, 227100 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 096)
- 1981 episodes, 227057
  - KPRC's summary of 1981 episodes, 227098 (Folder 4)
  - Jan. 03, 1981: Glasscock Vineyards, Fort Davis / Brit Bailey-Bailey's Prairie, Brazoria / Silk Screen Factory, Seguin / Sanchez-Saddle Shop, Victoria / Courtin, Brown, Dunn - Swiss Avenue, Dallas, 227097 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 097)
  - Jan. 10, 1981: Tandy Subway, Fort Worth / East Texas Autumn / Elder-Smoked Hams, Beeville / Bristol-Tarzan Collection, College Station / Carl Darr-Bullwhips, Paducah, 227096 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 098)
  - Jan. 17, 1981:Armstrong, Carr - Popeye/Spinach Cap, Crystal City / Jim Withrow-Lindale Candy Co. / B Wright-WWII Sub Capt, Aransas Pass / Stone - Thanksgiving Square, Dallas, 227095 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 099)
  - Jan. 24, 1981: Davis, Moon - Motorcycle "Warriors", Greenville / OL Lantz-Music Man, Port Arthur / Emma Seelye/Franklin Thomas - Civil War Spy, Houston / Doc Jack Habluetzel-Vet & Junk, Ingleside / B Jaxon-Log Cabins/Art, Salado, 227094 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 100)
  - Jan. 31, 1981: Smith, Brett - TX Illustrated Mag, Liberty / History-Miller Dam, Austin / Ranching Heritage Ctr, Lubbock / Edwards, Gist - Sculptors/Hermann Statue, Salado / Orbeck - Bosque County Museum, Clifton, 227093 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 101)
  - Feb. 7, 1981: Milligan - Quilting School, San Antonio / Tarpley - Texas Town Name Expert, Commerce / Lee, Patterson - Young Schoolhouse, Upton / Garrett - Champion Company, Port Isabel / Glen Rose - Texas and Dino Valley, 227092 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 102)
  - Feb. 14, 1981: Elwood, Denton, Smith - Cowpasture Bank, Rio Vista / Crawford - Odem-Crawford Home, Maydelle / Verter, Rohde - Railroad Musuem, Houston / Dale - Coff in Collector / Paso Real, Harlingen, 227091 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 103)
  - Feb. 21, 1981: Jambers - Crowther, Texas / Bucek - Pigs Feet Maker, Schulenburg / Cook's Fort, Alto / McCrary - McCrary House, Calvert / East Texas Oil Museum, Kilgore, 227090 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 104)
  - Feb. 28, 1981: Blaine, Lorrain - Mammoth Tusk, Cleburne / Fanita Lanier-Map Maker, Mineola / San Miguel - Botica Guadaupana RX, San Antonio / Briscoe - Oilfield Miniatures, Humble / Potton House, Big Spring, 227089 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 105)
  - March 07, 1981: Damaree-Bayside Distillery, Sunshine / Chief Bowles of the Cherokee / Greer-Tractors, Colleyville / Casey-Stuffed Animals WUMC, Houston / Davis Mountains, 227088 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 106)
  - March 14, 1981: Brink - Elissa Restoration, Galveston / Fannin-Outhouse Experts, Harvey / Brown - Hobby, Texas / Bennack - Photos of the "San Antonio Light" / Whistle Stop Ranch, Tyler, 227087 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 107)
  - March 21, 1981: Santa Anna-Chewing Gum, S.A. / Giddings Oil Boom / Springfield Ceramics, Navasota / Phillips-Longhorns, Brazoria Co. / John Nance Garner, Uvalde, 227086 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 108)
  - March 28, 1981: Burnham-Coyote Caller, Pleasanton / Hines - Wiergate, Texas / Lloyd Adams-Rock Art, Angleton / Avenger field, Sweetwater / Cleburne, Texas, 227085 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 109)
  - April 04, 1981: Hinson, Gulotta - Terrace Drive Inn, Texas City / Los Ojuelos Ranch, Webb Co. / Sherley Hardware Store, Anna / Moon's Balloons, Salado / Hranicky - Orange Crate, Orange Grove, 227084 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 110)
  - April 11, 1981: Inman RR Service Co., Baytown / Amigos de las Americas, Bastrop Chap. / Ford Auto Plants in Texas / Lowe-License Plates, Joaquin / Britt-Comfort Theater, 227083 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 111)
  - April 18, 1981: Los Adaes-Robeline, LA, Span TX / Jackson-Purse & Mattress Co., Edna / McMahan's Chapel, Sabine Co. / Marshall-Push-up Champ, San Antonio / Schnautz-Grist Mill, Uhland, 227082 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 112)
  - April 25, 1981: Frank Tolbert-Chili Parlor, Dallas / Bastrop Opera House / Lost DW Griffith Alamo Movie / Radio Controled Planes, Lake Jackson / La Puerta Cemetery-Soul's Day, 227081 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 113)
  - May 2, 1981: Solar Energy Studies, Uvalde / Watson - The Texas Kid, Dalls / Provident City / Pedrito - Faith Healer, Falfurrias, 227080 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 114)
  - May 9, 1981: Cedar Post Cutters, Gatesville / Downtown Restoration, Comfort / Don Odem - Pilot, Angleton / Bailey Harris, Van Alstyne / Market Square, San Antonio, 227079 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 115)
  - May 16, 1981: Pearl Brewery - Recycling Cans, San Antonio / Manchua, Near Van Alstyne / Kruse - Eichholt Home and Ranch, Brenham / Mine-Dupont - La Linda, West / Amicable Building, Waco, 227078 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 116)
  - May 23, 1981: Texas Buckskinners, Cibolo / Elizabeth Crockett, Acton / George Hermann, Houston / Seaquist Home, Mason, 227077 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 117)
  - May 30, 1981: Ned Green - Railroad Tycoon, Terrell / Opera House Hilton, Granbury / Calf Creek, near Brady / Casey Jones, San Augustine / New York Row, Anderson, 227076 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 118)
  - June 6, 1981: San Antonio Mission / Canary Islanders / Old Pics/Castroville / Praha / King William Street / Panna Maria/La Reunion / Institute of Texan Cultures, 227075 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 119)
  - Sept. 05, 1981: Smith - McDonald Observatory, Fort Davis / Crawfish Hunting (1973), Trinity / Alum Creek, Cottletown / Ammon Unerwood Home, E. Columbia / Sutton - Wildlife Park, Grand Prairie, 227074 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 120)
  - Sept. 12, 1981: Hasselbach - Pittsburg Hot Links, Pittsburg / Adams - 700 Springs Ranch, Junction / Taylor - Rock Castle & Lighthouse, Lampasas / Vic Emanuael-Nature Tours, Austin / TX 1st Ladies Gowns, Denton, 227073 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 121)
  - Sept. 19, 1981: WT Leon-Sunflowers, High Plains / Yorktown, Dewitt Co. / Pero, Rodgers - (H Ross) Perot Theater, Texarkana / Duckens Family Singers, Temple / Tonkawa-Pictographs, Crawford, 227072 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 122)
  - Sept. 26, 1981: Thurber Coal Mining, Erath Co. / Pat Post-Cake Decorator, Alief / Cal Farley's Boy''s Ranch, Tascosa / Folklife Festival, San Antonio, 227071 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 123)
  - Oct. 03, 1981: Cisco Swimming Hole, Eastland Co., The Woodlands Golfing Charities / Wright Plantation, Paris / Thadd Johnson-Outlaw Artist, Waco, 227070 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 124)
  - Oct. 10, 1981: Palo Duro Canyon, Panhandle / Clark - Desdemona-Boomtown Days / Bigden's Antique Village, Blanco / Cactus Garden, Langtry, 227069 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 125)
  - Oct. 17, 1981: Angora Goat Mohair, Rocksprings / Buckhorn Museum/Dominoes, Gatesville / Texas Navy, Galveston / Waggoner Empire, Vernon / Stark Mansion, Orange, 227068 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 126)
  - Oct. 24, 1981: Children's Pythian Home, Weatherford / McCoy's-Whittlers, Angleton / Ding Dong Daddy From Dumas / James Lee Baltimore, Kirbyille / Texas Forestry Museum, Lufkin, 227067 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 127)
  - Oct. 31, 1981: Heimer-Branding Irons, San Antonio / TX Parks & Wildlife Magazine, Austin / Shelton's Fort, Roxton / Camp Winiwaca, Rosebud / Robert Bruno-Steel House, Lubbock, 227066 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 128)
  - Nov. 07, 1981: Guayule Plant, Ft. Stockton/Marathon / Coldspring Jail, San Jacinto Co. / Kurtz - Coca Cola Collector, Houston / McReynolds - Chireno Stage Stop, Chireno / Belton Dam Mural, Bell Co., 227065 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 129)
  - Nov. 14, 1981: Berry-Turkey Egg Farm, Salado / Winzapfel - Windthorst, Archer Co. / Potter - Haunted Hill-Moody, Coryell Co. / Still, Kane-Wooden Star, Houston / Koliba Home-Museum, Columbus, 227064 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 130)
  - Nov. 21, 1981: Fire Ants, College Station / Samuel Bell Maxy House, Paris / Wilson - Helium Pavillion, Amarillo / Blazek-Sacred Gardens, New Waverly, 227063 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 131)
  - Nov. 28, 1981: Woo - Chinatown, Houston / Phillips - Tol Barret House, Nacogdoches / Hamilton Pool, Austin / Crain - Jean's Men's Bible Class, Nocona / Weaver - Pioneer Village, Canyon, 227062 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 132)
  - Dec. 5, 1981: Railroad Centennial, Big Spring / Llewellyn - Chinese Shar-Pei Dogs, Alvin / Music Box Collections, Hopkins County Museum / Fannin Battleground, Goliad, 227061 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 133)
  - Dec. 12, 1981: King - Cattle Cops, Fort Worth / Simpson, Collins - State line Station and Bar, Reeves County / Yelderman - Dump King of Damon, TX / Tips Building, Austin, 227060 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 134)
  - Dec. 19, 1981: Holmes, Trammell -Azle, Texas / Texas White House (Sterling Mansion), La Porte / Pakan Community, Wheeler County, Texas Panhandle / Christmas Card Collector, Corpus Christi / Fire Museum of Texas, Dallas, 227059 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 135)
  - Dec. 26, 1981: Texas Historical Markers, San Antonio / Sunset Trading Post, Sunset / Tic Toc Ranch, Floresville / Sumner - Homestead Ranch, Hillister / Burtz - Sad monkey Train Ride, Palo Duro Canyon, 227058 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 136)
- 1982 episodes, 227017
  - KPRC's summary of 1982 episodes, 227056 (Folder 5)
  - Jan. 02, 1982: Fort Griffin - Fandangle, Albany / Lynne de Coux - Portrait Doll Maker, Silsbee / Sprinkle - Fulton Old Timers, Fulton / Bragg - Texas Broadcast Museum, Dallas, 227055 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 137)
  - Jan. 09, 1982: Route 66 - Panhandle / Mobettie-Panhandle Settlement / Adkins-Walking Sticks, Austin / Prarie Dog-Towe Park, Snyder / Old Jail Museum, Albany, 227054 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 138)
  - Jan. 16, 1982: Landmark Inn, Castroville / H Graham-Clocks, Marble Falls / J Wilson-Antique Guns, Pyote / Clell Conner-Cowboy Singer, Liberty / Spradley-Telephones, McGregor, 227053 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 139)
  - Jan. 23, 1982: Igloo Coolers, Houston / H Schillings-Fox Hound Breeder, Center / End of Playland Park, San Antonio / HW Caylor-Frontier Artist, Big Spring / Ice Storm of 1982, San Antonio, 227052 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 140)
  - Jan. 30, 1982: Albert Sydney Johnston-Civil War / J Turner-Dollhouses, Rockport / Vernon Dalhart-Musician, Jefferson / Coldsprings Canyon, Coldsprings, 227051 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 141)
  - Feb. 06, 1982: J Carlin-Old Ford Parts, Beaumont / Chuck Wagon History / AJ Schubert-Theatre Artist, Rosenberg / R Dawson-Toy Trains, San Antonio / Freeman Plantation, Jefferson, 227050 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 142)
  - Feb. 13, 1982: T Haslam-Prosthetics, Houston / G Bankston-Oil Patch Artist, Odessa / Miller's Custom Book Binder, Austin / Wooden Drawbridge, Sargent, 227049 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 143)
  - Feb. 20, 1982: Shlabach, Moore - Old Ingram Restored, Kerr Co. / Groveton without Lumber & RR / Forest Fire Fighter History / Jane Long & Mirabeau Lamar, Richmond, 227048 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 144)
  - Feb. 27, 1982: Wrights-Grave Hunters, Montgomery Co. / Belton Mansions, Bell County / Juanita Stigen-Min. Outhouses, Midland / Manor, Texas / Studio 205, Victoria, 227047 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 145)
  - March 06, 1982: Ruth, H.C. Wilkes, Tom Lacy - Lacy Dogs, Marble Falls / Robert E. McKinney-Alamo Artist, Alvin / Larry and Roxanna Hatfield-Jukeboxes, Snyder / Downes-Aldrich House, Crockett / Stark Museum, Orange, 227046 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 146)
  - March 27, 1982: Landy Zeh-Arm Wrestler, Magnolia / Colleen Urbanek - Colleen's Books, Houston / Givrin, Texas - Pecos Co. / Caddo Indian Mound House, Alto / Southwest Craft Center, San Antonio, 227045 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 147)
  - March 20, 1982: Summer Mummers, Midland / Sutton-Taylor Feud, Cuero / Pappy Oliver-Toy Maker, Sheppard / David Mitschke-Sawmill Man, Loebau / Old Jail Museum, Bandera, 227044 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 148)
  - March 27, 1982: La Colombe D'or Hotel, Houston / Uvalde Opera House / Chihuahuan Desert Research Inst. / Ancel Nunn-Lithographer, Palestine / Old SAAP RR Line, Kerrville, 227043 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 149)
  - April 03, 1982: John Thompson, Marine Science institute, Port Aransas / David Kircher - Violet Museum / Russel and Audrey Paul - Token Collectors, Crockett / George Boyle - La Boarde Hotel, Rio Grande City, 227042 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 150)
  - April 10, 1982: Brent Harnish - Pioneer Flour, San Antonio / Laura and Pete Crowley - Smallest Catholic Church, Warrenton / Ghost Town, Belle Plain / Dan Brasher, Winfred Taylor - Community Cotton Pick, Ackerly / Lindabeth Oldham - Red Horse Museum, Mercedes, 227041 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 151)
  - April 17, 1982: Dr. Charles Simpson - Peanut Research, Stephenville / Grover Die - Woodville Syrup Mill / Christ Church Cathedral, Houston / Marj Remmers - Windmill Country Store, San Antonio, 227040 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 152)
  - April 24, 1982: Owens-Black Beauty Ranch, Brownsboro / Inez Unger-Bone Artist, San Antonio / Shudde Brothers-Hats, Houston / LBJ's Homes tours, Johnson City / Bud Horn-Martha's Kitchen, Weslaco, 227039 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 153)
  - May 01, 1982: S. Cheatham-Wild Plants, Alto / Tyler-Crawfish Boil, Houston / Kronkosky Tower, Boerne / Toyah, Texas / Bill Clements, Bill Hobby, Bill Clayton - Capitol Groundbreaking, Austin, 227038 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 154)
  - May 08, 1982: Bales-Electric Cars, Austin / Dwight Holmes-Artist, San Angelo / Genevieve Vollentine - Gonzales Jail Museum / Geoffery Michael - Water Works Restaurant, Waco / Griffith Homeplace, Dobbin, 227037 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 155)
  - May 15, 1982: Estevan-1st Black Man in Texas / Julio Voirin-Violin Expert, San Antonio / Stagecoach Era (5-1979) / Kleb-Farm Collection, Tomball / Fred Tinnin, Buzz Kelley - Brushy Creek Inn, Round Rock, 227036 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 156)
  - May 22, 1982: Space Ed Program, NASA, San Antonio / Jalapeno Sam, San Angelo / Immortal Performances, Austin / Bilvins Home, Amarillo / EOT Pad ( Child for a Day), 227035 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 157)
  - Sep. 04, 1982: Jim Paul - Diablos Baseball, El Paso / Beaty-Orton House, Jasper / A.G. Wilson - Larait Rope maker, Marshall / Senior Olympics, Hondo / Elmo Jackson - Elmo's Roadhouse, Corpus, 227034 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 158)
  - Sep. 11, 1982: Ida Mae Stark's Wedding Cakes, Jacksboro / Kickapoo Indians of Eagle Pass / Dan Blocker, O'Donnell / Audie Ray - Hudson Autom Museum, 227033 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 159)
  - Sep. 18, 1982: Texas Ragtops / John Wesley de Vilbiss - Oakisland Methodist Church / Mexican Cattle, Langtry / Wes Phillips, Alibates National Monument, Potter County, 227032 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 160)
  - Sept. 25, 1982: H.L. Ayers - Wind Generators, Crowell / Reverley-Dentist/Undertaker, San Antonio / McAllen Nature Center / Melvin Hatton - Last Texaco Housing, Bridge City / George Crawford - Gage Hotel, Marathon, 227031 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 161)
  - Oct. 02, 1982: Hot Springs of West Texas / McWhorter-Mdm Alexander Dolls, Corpus / Masters-Backyard Worshop, Conroe / Museum of Printing History, Houston, 227030 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 162)
  - Oct. 09, 1982: Ceramics Class, Coldspring / Pampa Texas / Faison Home, La Grange / Westcave Preserve, Travis Co. / Galveston Transportation Museum, 227029 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 163)
  - Oct. 16, 1982: Purdue, Chisholm, Levenson, Stein: String Quartet of Midland / Forenberry - Miniature House Maker, Woodville / Battle of Velasco, Freeport / Earl Gilbert - Houston Architect / Taniguchi Garden, Austin, 227028 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 164)
  - Oct. 23, 1982: Xit Ranch, Panhandle / Abbott - Wildflower Seed Man, Hill Country / Gray - Tolar Kitchen, Woodville / Sorenson - Marine Biology Museum / Low - Vanishing Texas River Tour, Hill Country, 227027 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 165)
  - Oct. 30, 1982: McKissack, Moore, Blount - Orange Show, Houston / Gose, Barry - Retama Polo Center, San Antonio / Tabor - Chainsaw Woodcarver, Whiteright / Clark Hotel, Van horn / Zaharis - Babe Memorial Beaumont, 227026 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 166)
  - Nov. 06, 1982: Tigoa / McMahon - Billy Boomeran, South Padre Island / Old Cora Courthouse / E.B. Ribble, odessa Architect / Jandt - Jandt Homestead, Seguin, 227025 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 167)
  - Nov. 13, 1982: Murrin, Mitchell - Chisholm Trail Ride, Fort Worth / Gentry - Annie's Attic, Big Sandy / Leon hale, Houston / Wesley Brethren Church, 227024 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 168)
  - Nov. 20, 1982: Schaefer - Schulenburg Observatory, Houston / Woodbine Hotel, Madisonville / D'Hanis, TX / Miertschin, Zapalac - La Grange Journal / Bryson, Wall - San Jacinto Plaza, El Paso, 227023 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 169)
  - Nov. 27, 1982: Wangberg - Ant Collection, Lubbock / Nance - Texas Cedar Products, Smithville / Peckerwood hill Cemetery (Captain Joe Byrd Cemetery), Huntsville / George Washington Baines House, Salado, 227022 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 170)
  - Dec. 04, 1982: Grill, Milner - Dittlinger Library, New Braunfels / Guthrie Courthosue, King County / Levering, Winslett, Behn - Gallery 71, Smithville / Captain Victor Delgado, Port Isabell / Sydnor-Powhatan House, Galveston, 227021 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 171)
  - Dec. 11, 1982: Wisdom - Mo-Pac Man, Dispatching Station, Spring / A.B.J. Hammett, Victoria / Boyd Family Reunion, Callahan Co / Zubia - Rosa's Cantina, El Paso / Longhorn Museum, Pleasanton, 227020 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 172)
  - Dec. 18, 1982: Architect LEGO Contest, Houston / Shiyers - Old Timers & Oil Derricks, Hull/Daisetta / Waldrop-Country Store, Lamesa / Anderson-Pet Furniture, Rosenberg / Lone Star Hiking Trail, Huntsville, 227019 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 173)
  - Dec. 25, 1982: Schaler-Rolls Royce Collection, Midland / Alexander-Wood Lock Maker, W. Orange / Rural School, Fashing / Quilting Bee, Huntsville, 227018 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 174)
- 1983 episodes, 226978
  - KPRC's summary of 1983 episodes, 227016 (Folder 6)
  - Jan. 01, 1983: Chilton - Trolley, San Antonio / Nonnie Smith-Military Collection, Odessa / Taylor's Paperbacks Plus, Austin / DES Woods-Wildlife Mgmt, Edwards Co. / Bill Bean-East TX History, Kilgore, 227015 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 175)
  - Jan. 08, 1983: Hammet - Martin de Leon, Victoria / Bob Roberson-Buggy Man, Levelland / Joel Dyer-Old Home Buff, Galveston / Comanche County Museum, 227014 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 176)
  - Jan. 15, 1983: Merrick-Gone With Wind, Lamesa / Cindy Hickok-Soft Sculpress, Houston / Jewel Babb-Faith Healer, Valentine / Log Cabins-Zilker Park, Austin, 227013 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 177)
  - Jan. 22, 1983: Couch-Wild Ponies, West Columbia / RJ Delwaide Pottery, Arlington / La Mesilla, El Paso / Schultz-Model RailRoad, Frelsburg / Dogtown, Texas, 227012 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 178)
  - Jan. 29, 1983: Allen Academy, Bryan / Mitchell - Blum Building, Galveston / Jim Lee-Wood Hummer, Reagan Wells / TeePee Village, Abilene / Ft Bliss-Artillery Museum, El Paso, 227011 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 179)
  - Feb. 05, 1983: Walter Borski-Blacksmith, Anderson / Gutzon and Lincoln - Borglum-Sculptor, San Antonio / Ransdell-Clock Maker, College Station / Climer - Chicken Charlie's, Balmorhea, 227010 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 180)
  - Feb. 12, 1983: Hometel Business, Hou-Dal-El Paso, Petrik-Etched Glass, La Grange / Blankenship-Cowboy, Temple / Clark - Building Restoration, Georgetown, 227009 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 181)
  - Feb. 19, 1983: Torres Boot Co., Raymondville / Douglas 'Wrong Way' Corrigan, Galveston / Chavez-Model Airplanes, San Antonio / Brink - Elissa Restoration, Galveston / Ranger Peak Tramway, El Paso, 227008 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 182)
  - Feb. 26, 1983: Mounted Patrol, Fort Worth / Main Street Project, Georgetown / Beaumier Iron Works, Brenham / Bill Goodspeed-Photographer/Pigeon Trainer / Museum of Southwest, Midland, 227007 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 183)
  - March 5, 1983: 3 Bed & Breakfasts, Corpus Christi / Fisk-Environmentalist, Austin / Willson-Glass Artist, San Antonio / Joens - TX Rose Coffee Mill, Heidenheimer, 227006 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 184)
  - March 12, 1983: Grimes - Grist Mill, Mount Union / Lancaster Hotel, Houston / Ernst - General Store, McFaddin / McClendon Home, Tyler, 227005 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 185)
  - March 19, 1983: Badu House, Llano / Log Cabins, Donie / Franciscan Monks, Galveston / Bubba Voss-Circus Collection, Orange, 227004 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 186)
  - March 26, 1983: Kolonko - Model T Restorer, Victoria / Flukinger, Harrah - Neon Artists, Hempstead / Winnetka Heights, Dallas / It's a Young World, Texas / German/English School, San Antonio, 227003 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 187)